To build rapport means to develop a relationship, especially one of mutual
trust or emotional affinity. This sounds like a daunting task. We spend our
lives working on our relationships with family, friends, and associates. Is it
possible to establish a relationship with an audience, especially one filled
with strangers, in the course of half-hour talk or half-day workshop? The
answer is, of course, yes.
  Naturally, the relationship you develop with a roomful of people won't be
the same as it would be with a small group sitting around a restaurant table
or with a one-on-one session with a prospective client. But it is possible to
establish the kind of accord that leads to trust and affinity.
  There's been significant interest recently in the concept of EQ-emotional
intelligence. Individuals with a significant EQ are empathetic, intuitive, and
perceptive, with a highly developed ability to put themselves in other
people's shoes. Research on the subject shows that among people of equal
intelligence, those with well-established EQ are more likely to be high
achievers because of their ability to predict other people's behavior and to
understand their motivations.