Slides are extremely versatile visual aids that allow the presenter to share
photographic images, drawings, and other artwork, words, numbers, charts,
graphs, and timelines with the audience. In the past slides were expensive
and time consuming to produce. Today, computers and desktop publishing
programs reduce the time and expense considerably.
  In fact, a relative novice can now produce sophisticated slides using
software programs like Corel's Presentation and Microsoft's PowerPoint for
the PC, or Persuasion by Adobe for Macintosh. There are many more
programs available, and new ones are being developed all the time.
  The versatility and scope of slide design is as broad as any area of
graphic art, and software packages offer exciting and attractive design
options, though learning how to navigate your way through the program does
take some time. Most community colleges offer extensive computer
classes, including courses on graphic design. Even without training, using a
little effort and the templates in the software, you can create attractive slides
that incorporate interesting and readable typography, graphs, charts, maps,
clip art, and other visuals.