Using humor in your presentation isn't always about telling jokes. It's about
introducing amusing, whimsical, comical, or otherwise entertaining elements
that make it easier for you to make a connection with your audience, to put you
and them at ease, and to reinforce your message.
  Presenters use humor at the start of their talks to loosen up the audience,
to release tension, and to build rapport. By weaving humor through a
presentation, the presenter helps his audience remain alert. And by linking
an amusing anecdote or one-liner with a key point, he can add emphasis.
  Some presenters use jokes to add humor, but this can be risky. Very few of
us are born comedians. Professional entertainers whose stock in trade are funny
jokes spend their lives perfecting their timing and delivery, and many fail.
Even superstars like Don Rickles or David Letterman have had jokes fall flat.
Because they are practically icons of the entertainment industry, Letterman and
Rickles can afford the occasional bomb. You can't.
  The other problem with jokes is that humor in them is almost always at
someone's expense. Can you risk the possibility of offending even one member
of your audience with your joke?